ANDREW LONDON



UI/UX ENGINEER

CONTACTS

704.287.1152

| | london.andrewd@gmail.com | |
|--------------|-----------------------------|--|
| in | www.linkedin.com/in/alondon | |
| | | |
| SKILLS | | |
| TECHNICAL | | |
| React | | |
| React Native | | |
| Angular 1.x | | |
| CSS/Sass | | |
| HTML | _ | |
| Node | JS | |
| SQL | | |
| SOFTWARE | | |

EDUCATION

2016

Sketch

Invision

JIRA

Frontend Engineering Track

The Iron Yard

Charleston, SC

2014

B.S. Sociology

College of Charleston

Charleston, SC

2013

Web 101-105

Charleston Digital Corridor

Charleston, SC

PROFILE

Meticulous software engineer with 5+ years experience as a frontend focused developer. Highly proficient in HTML, CSS and Javascript with a deep appreciation for clean and consistent user experiences. Looking to grow into a leadership role with the opportunity to both mentor and learn from other developers

WORK EXPERIENCE

SENIOR UI/UX ENGINEER

07.2020 - Present | Rhinogram

- Work with company stakeholders to iterate over new and existing features by using Sketch and Invision to design and manage complex and detailed prototypes.
- Bring UI/UX consistency across all of our platforms by creating standalone, maintainable components and managing Rhinostyle, our open sourced component library.
- Reduce end to end development time by introducing and leading bi-weekly frontend architecture meetings with the product and engineering teams.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

10.2018 - 07.2020 | Rhinogram

- Spearheaded the implementation of a real-time WebRTC video chat feature, with cross browser consistency over a wide range of mobile and desktop browsers.
- Created an intricate roles and permissions feature, allowing for highly granular rules permitting access to certain segments of the application.
- Developed seamless user experiences for our web and mobile applications using React,
 React Native and NodeJS.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

11.2016 - 10.2018 | Launchpeer

- Took client ideas from concept to launch by building mobile and web applications across a wide range of sectors and scales.
- Wrote clean, reusable and maintainable code based on industry best practices.
- Communicated directly with clients, providing them with regular updates about the progress and development of their projects.

WEB DEVELOPER

09.2016 - 02.2017 | Benefitfocus

- Designed, developed and implemented features and solutions for Benefitfocus' primary public facing website, benefitfocus.com.
- Deployed weekly builds and tested new features across different browsers.
- Built pixel perfect HTML email templates from PSD mockups.